本字幕由大家字幕组原创翻译制作仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为若因私自散布传播造成法律问题 本字幕组概不负责更多影视请搜索并关注新浪微博  大家字幕组
翻译：肉肉萌小受 鑫鑫美少女 叉叉美少年
翻译：抹茶苏 Cindy 汉谟拉 小俊仔儿
时间轴特效：山楂 娇娇 静宇 压制：大汪不开森 Paradise 校对：肉肉萌小受
狼・厅
第1季 第3集
公元1531年 自胁迫教皇失败后
亨利八世向国会要求赋予他
英格兰教区内至高无上的权力
以求自行废除与凯瑟琳王后的婚姻关系
那些罗马教廷的死忠 与日渐兴起的异端邪说 展开了激烈的斗争
其中最主要的死忠是 大法官阁下 托马斯 莫尔爵士
"从前在百姓中有假先知起来 将来在你们中间
Fuerunt vero et pseudoprophetae in populo,
也必有假师傅
sicut et in vobis erunt magistri mendaces...
私自引进害人的异端邪说
..qui introducunt sectas perditionis,
连买他们的主他们也不承认
et eum qui emit eos, Dominum negant,
自取速速的灭亡"  [《圣经新约》 - 彼得后书]
superducentes sibi celerem perditionem.
克伦威尔学士？
Master Cromwell?
女士 您女儿应该站站好
Madam, your daughter should sit.
立正站直
Stand up straight.
这位是克伦威尔学士
This is Master Cromwell.
他以前是个放债者 现在负责撰写所有的法律章程
He used to be a money-lender. Now he writes all the laws.
我听说你的新议案
I have heard all about your new bill
诱使国王将自己视为英格兰教区的首脑？
inducing the King to describe himself as the head of the church?
只有教皇冕下一人是全世界教区的最高首脑
The Pope is the head of the church everywhere.
所有政权的合法性都是经过...
The lawfulness of all government flows from the...
经过...
..from...
坐下来吧 玛丽公主殿下
Will you not sit down, Princess Mary?
这椅子不会凉着您
It's just the heat.
我请求王后您换一下思路
I beg your madam to consider it in this way -
国王陛下只不过是重新定义了一个职位的概念 何况古有先例...
the King has merely defined a position which ancient precedents...
自古而有的先例？
Ancient precedents?
那不过是你这三个月里编出来的先例而已
Precedents that you've invented these last three months.
至于您说"诱使" 王后您是知道的国王陛下是不会轻易被引导的
As for "induced" - Your Highness knows the King cannot be led.
但能被怂恿诱惑
But he can be enticed.
他连一句再见都没有说 抛弃一切离开了
He has ridden off without saying goodbye.
他以前从未这样做过 从未有之！
He's never done that before. Never.
这个 我想他是去切特西那边狩猎几天而已
Well, I think he means to hunt out of Chertsey for a few days.
是和那个女人一起去
With the woman. The person.
国王陛下去了另外的行宫
Your Highness will be going to another palace.
他挑了在赫特福德郡的莫尔家
He has chosen the More, in Hertfordshire,
您也知道 那里气候宜人
which as you know is very comfortable.
那曾经是你们某个红衣主教的宫殿吧
It was one of your cardinal's houses, wasn't it?
所以必定是奢华至极的
So it's bound to be lavish.
希望如此
I expected this.
但我不希望他随便派个你这样的人来告诉我
But I didn't expect he would send a man like you to tell me.
我想给你样东西
I want to give you something.
当作礼物
A present.
任何你想要的东西
Name anything you want.
你想要什么
What is it?
你的那项法案
This bill of yours.
这不是我的法案
It's not my bill.
从主教们身上夺取权力 再赋予亨利为教会首脑
Taking power from the bishops, making Henry head of the church.
你难道不害怕么
Aren't you afraid?
害怕什么
Of what?
有一个叫伊丽莎白 巴顿的女孩做出来预言
There's this girl called Elizabeth Barton making prophecies.
他们管她叫 圣女
They're calling her the Holy Maid.
她说如若亨利娶了安妮 他的王位终将不保
She's saying Henry won't reign for a year if he marries Anne.
还有说月亮旁边新冒出来了一个星星
And there's a new star by the moon, and the...
那不是星星 那是彗星
It's not a star. It's a comet.
上次它出现还是在约翰国王在位时
..and the last time it appeared was under King John
那时万物凋零 寸草不生
and the cattle stopped breeding and the grass stopped growing
千山鸟飞绝
and the birds fell from the sky.
如果真的发生这些事 我们倒是可以调整政策的方向性了
Well, I'm sure if that happens, we can reverse our policy.
我一点也不信预兆这回事
I don't believe in omens.
他们逮捕了一个律师 詹姆斯 班罕
They've arrested a barrister - James Bainham.
你认识他的吧？
You know him, don't you?
对 他是个好人
Yes. He's a good man.
但他被搜出了英译版的圣经
He was handing out the gospel in English.
如果他们严刑逼供怎么办
What if they torture Bainham?
如果他供出了你怎么办
What if he...gives names?
不用担心我 托马斯 莫尔早就知道了
What's that to me? Thomas More already knows my name.
同意法案的请站我右手边 反对的站左手边
Those for the bill to my right, those against to my left.
我想 法案通过了！ 通过！
I think the "ayes" have it. The "ayes" have it!
国王陛下
Your Majesty.
恭喜你了 我猜这分队投票是你的主意吧
Congratulations. I take it the division of the house was your idea?
我想这样才能让国王陛下一目了然他的追随者
I thought this way His Majesty could see who was with him
及反对者们
and who against him.
至少也要分清国会中的派别
In the Commons, at least.
我知道斯蒂芬是反对法案的 克伦威尔
I know Stephen is opposed to the bill, Cromwell.
我也不想有个只会应声附和的仆从
I don't want a servant who will agree with everything.
我需要的是能应付论战的人才
I need men who aren't afraid of controversy.
我知道你们俩一直争论不休
Now, I know you two quarrel.
但现在 你们必须要学会通力合作
You must learn to pull together.
这个寒冬 你们俩 轭不离犁 犁不离轭 一起干活
This winter, you have to be yoked to the plough.
你应该知道让上议院通过法案并不是件易事
You won't find it so easy passing your bill through the House of Lords.
托马斯 莫尔和古老的家族们都是支持教皇的
Thomas More and the old aristocracy are for the Pope
且并不怕国王知晓
and not afraid to say so.
这个嘛 等着看好了 沃罕大主教
Well, we'll see. Archbishop Warham.
那位被你藏在教区里的女先知 伊丽莎白 巴顿
This um, prophetess you harbour in your diocese - Eliza Barton?
她还好吗
How is she getting on?
你想要干嘛 克伦威尔
What do you want, Cromwell?
我听说她四处传播
Well, I hear that she's telling people
如国王娶了安妮夫人 那就不久于王位了
that if the King marries Lady Anne, he has only a year to reign.
我只想知道谁教她这么说的
I just wondered who is controlling her.
她也许只是一个简单的乡村姑娘 但她确实天赋异禀
She may be a simple country girl but she has a genuine gift.
是啊 确实是
She does, doesn't she?
我想她也能预知您是因何而亡的
I hear she can tell you where your dead relatives are.
如在天堂 她将更高亢
If it's in Heaven, she speaks with a higher voice,
如在地狱 她将更低沉
if in Hell, with a deep voice.
她也可以一见面
She can also tell what sins
就说出这人的罪行
weigh upon a man as soon as she meets him.
她见到你 会说什么呢
What would she make of you?
安特卫普之行怎么样 [比利时城市]
How was Antwerp?
很高兴到家了
Glad to be home.
噢
Oh.
装装样子的 怕沿途出乱子
For show. In case I got stopped.
嗯
Hmm.
- 嗯哼     - 在中间的夹缝里
- Mm-hmm.  - Centre seam.
- 他说什么?           - 你一直带着却没有读吗
- What does he say?   - You carried it without reading it?
为了以防不测 我不想提前知道
I didn't want to know. In case.
如果托马斯 莫尔 想方设法要接近你的话
If Thomas More came anywhere near you,
我会将他拖出他的威斯敏斯特教区
I'd drag him out of his court in Westminster
然后用鹅卵石上砸他的脑袋 直到把上帝怜爱砸进去
and beat his head on the cobbles until I'd knocked some of God's love into it.
- 汀代尔会回来吗            - 嗯
- Will Tynedale come back?  - M'hm.
只要国王同意将圣经译成英文
When the King says yes to the scripture being translated into English.
但即使那样 他也不会相信莫尔给他安全保证 因为
But even then, he won't trust More to give him safe conduct, because
莫尔曾说 根本不必对一个异教徒的信守承诺
More says you don't have to keep the promise you made to a heretic.
总之 汀代尔仍在严词抗争国王的离婚案
Anyway, Tynedale still refuses to support the King's divorce.
你也许会想 他作为英格兰国王的朋友
You'd think he'd bend a point of principle to make
不应该那么坚持原则的
a friend of the King of England.
但其实不然 汀代尔和莫尔 他们俩还真是配
But, no. Tynedale and More - they deserve each other.
俩杂种都装的像正人君子一样
These mules who pose as men.
夫人
My lady.
弓有问题
It's the bow.
当然 应该是支架的高度
No doubt. It could be the brace height.
可以帮我们换下弓吗
Could we swap the bows, please?
她还是和小时候一样
She was the same in the nursery.
"罗宾汉"在哪  我已将派人找他去了
Where's Robin Hood? I have dispatches.
他到日落时 才会见他们
He won't look at them until sundown.
他之后就不忙了吗
Won't he be occupied then?
她在一点一点诱惑他
She's selling herself by the inch.
她每露出一截大腿 就要很多现金礼物
She wants a cash present for every advance above her knee.
并且她的腿很长
She's got long legs.
等国王能一捣黄龙时 国家估计也破产了
By the time he reaches her secret part, the nation'll be bankrupt!
我...我听到了一个谣言...
I er, I had heard a rumour...
她没怀 否则我会知道的
She isn't. I would know.
如果她把衣服加厚了 我也是要帮她垫衣服的人
If she thickened at all, I'd be the one to have to let out her clothes.
我知道她腰围的每分每寸
I know her waist by the inch.
而且 她不可能怀的 因为他们还没有...
Besides, she can't be. Because they still haven't.
- 她会告诉你这些     - 当然
- She'd tell you?    - Of course.
一气之下说的
Out of spite.
我想要一份工作
I want a job.
正式的职位
An official post.
在珠宝宫殿最好
In the Jewel House, perhaps?
我会告诉她的
I'll tell her.
她让汤姆 怀特成了一名诗人 哈利 珀西为之疯狂
She made Tom Wyatt a poet and Harry Percy mad.
我肯定她对你也有些想法
I'm sure she has some idea what to make you.
上周 在格林威治
Last week, at Greenwich,
一个修士给我们传道
a Friar preached to us
讲的是关于一个好国王被一个淫妇所毁的故事
about the good king who was corrupted by the wicked Jezebel.
她建了一座异教徒的寺宇
Apparently she built a pagan temple
并且让巴尔的信徒进入礼拜  [堕落神 耶和华最大的敌人]
and let the priests of Baal into the palace.
最后她被扔出了窗外
She ended up being thrown out of a window.
现在我成了那个淫妇了 你懂没
I'm the Jezebel, you see
而你就是信仰巴尔的教徒
and you're the priests of Baal.
我明白
I see.
莫尔逮捕了一名律师 詹姆斯 班罕
More has arrested a barrister, James Bainham.
- 你想让我做什么                          - 和国王求求情
- What do you expect me to do about it?   - Talk to the King.
你知道该如何取悦他的
You know how to please him, I suppose?
用我的处女之身换你的律师
My maidenhead for your lawyer?
我保证他会被释放的
He'll be released.
嗯...
Well...
..小比尔耐就没有释放
..Little Bilney wasn't.
他们在诺威奇把他活活烧死了
They burnt him in Norwich.
只要你的律师朋友公开道歉认错 他就马上被释放
Your barrister friend will recant and he'll be released.
如果他不呢
And if he doesn't?
那他就是个傻瓜
Then he's a fool.
人不为己 天诛地灭
People should say whatever will keep them alive.
难道你不是吗
You would, wouldn't you?
你抱的什么
What's that?
啊
Ah.
给一个小女孩的礼物
It's a gift for one of your women.
就是那个经常哭的小女孩
The little girl who always cries.
怎么了
What?
你难道没听说吗
Didn't you hear?
没有 什么事
No, what?
她的父亲 亲爱的老约翰 西摩爵士
Her father - dear old Sir John Seymour?
在干草棚里 他和他儿子爱德华的妻子 被捉奸了
He was caught in the hayloft with his son Edward's wife.
好像前两年里 他每周都能和她鬼混
It seems he's had her every week for the last two years.
然后爱德华就把他妻子打发进了尼姑庵去
Edward's put the wife into a nunnery
所以我可不认为我们能很快在议会上看到亲爱的老约翰爵士了
and I don't think we'll see dear old Sir John at court soon.
那他女儿 叫珍妮的 对吧
And the daughter? Jane, is it?
那个脸色苍白的女孩吗 去了威尔特郡
Pasty-face? Gone to Wiltshire.
其实她最好的选择也是去尼姑庵
It's her best bet to get into a nunnery too.
现在没有人想娶这种懦弱的人
No-one want will want to marry the milksop now.
这是什么东西
What is it?
这只是...
It's only...
...一本有着编织图案的书
..a book of needlework patterns.
你是喜欢她吗
You don't LIKE her...do you?
因为我不能确定 你送她礼物这事是否合适
Because I'm not sure it's proper for you to send her a present.
哎呀 这又不是什么薄伽丘的童话集
Well, it's not like it's tales from Boccaccio.
噢 他们居然称薄伽丘那鬼东西叫童话!
Oh, they could tell Boccaccio a tale!
那些身在狼厅的罪人们
Those sinners at Wolf Hall.
嗯哼?
Mm-hmm?
大法官阁下
Lord Chancellor.
你应该先知会我一声的
You should have warned me.
您要吃些东西吗
You'll have something to eat?
- 谢谢 不了       - 那要喝点什么 来点酒?
- Thank you, no.  - Something to drink then? Some wine?
你的朋友 班罕
Your friend, Bainham?
他已经抛弃了那些异端邪说
He has recanted his heresy
被释放了
and been set free.
我觉得你应该先知晓
I thought you should know.
是啊 谢谢你
Well, thank you.
我却听说 他被用刑了
I heard that he'd been put to the rack.
为了拯救他的灵魂 我是主张对他用鞭刑的
To save his soul, I would have had him whipped,
我主张将他绑着手腕吊起来与钢铁一同燃烧
I'd have had him burnt with irons,
与钢铁...一同燃烧
I'd have had him...hung by his wrists.
在过去十年中 土耳其人已经占领了贝尔格莱德
In these last ten years, the Turks have taken Belgrade.
他们已经将营火烧到了布达的大图书馆
They have lit their campfires in the great library at Buda.
这距离他们被困在维也纳 不过只有两年而已
It is only two years since they were at the gates of Vienna.
你为什么还要在基督世界中 再搞一次大破坏呢
Why would you want to make another breach in the walls of Christendom?
英格兰国王 并不是异教徒
The King of England is not an infidel.
- 我也不是    - 你不是吗
- Nor am I.   - Aren't you?
我认为你的信仰是利益至上
I think your faith is for purchase.
只要出价满意 你甚至都会去效忠苏丹[奥斯曼帝国的最高统治者]
I think you would serve the Sultan if the price was right.
不要以为你现在是个小小议员 你就可以背着国王
You think because you're a councillor you can negotiate
跟那些异教徒打交道 你错了
with heretics behind the King's back. You're wrong.
我已经知道你那些往来的信件了
I know about your letters that come and go.
也知道你一直在和汀代尔保持联系
I know you are in communication with Tyndale.
你是在威胁我吗
Are you threatening me?
只是感兴趣而已
I'm just interested.
是 是的
Yes. Yes.
这是我一直在做的事
That's precisely what I'm doing.
你还是没告诉我你想要什么礼物
You still haven't told me what you want as a present.
我妈妈知道了
My mother knows.
我们的事
About us.
我...我想...
I...I think...
我想我们已经做了我们该做的事
I think we've done what we have
因为莉兹去世的时候 我们都很震惊
because when Liz died, we were shocked.
我们很遗憾
We were sorry.
但我认为我们现在都该放下了
I think we have to leave off that now.
如果...如果我丈夫...
If...if my husband had -
上帝宽恕我 但每到冬天我都觉得会是他的最后一段生命
God forgive me but every winter I think is his last -
然后 当然...我想和你... 毫无疑问
then of course, I would, without question.
但是...
But then...
法律不会允许这样的 所以...
the law wouldn't allow that, so...
如果你想要续娶 梅茜有给你准备一长串名单
If, if you want to marry, Mercy has her list.
你也可能有了心仪的人选 也许还是我们不认识的人 所以...
You probably have your own list, with names on it we don't know, so...
莉兹
Liz.
约翰娜
Johane.
佛朗西斯 布莱恩来了 有些不好的事发生了
Francis Bryan is here. It's something bad.
他是安妮的表亲 我一定要...
He's Anne's cousin. I'll have to...
珀西的妻子怎么说
What does Percy's wife say?
她说她会去请求国会准许离婚
She says she's going to petition Parliament for divorce.
她说她已经有两年是自己独睡的了
She says he hasn't shared her bed for two years,
而且她问他原因时 他说他不能
and when she asked him why he said he couldn't.
那为什么她要等了两年之后才问
Why has she waited two years to ask?
她一直在问
She has been asking.
昨晚 他终于承认了他做不到
And last night, he finally admitted he can't sleep with her
- 因为他们没有真正结婚                 - 什么?
- because they're not really married.  - What?
因为哈利 珀西实际上是与安妮 博林结了婚的
Because Harry Percy's actually married to Anne Boleyn.
把它们弄下来!
Bring them down!
我们已经把大部分碎玻璃渣扫干净了
We've swept up most of the broken glass.
关上门 佛朗西斯 别让任何人进来
Shut the door, Francis and don't let anybody in.
我建议我们把安妮的东西打包 然后送她去肯特
I suggest we pack Anne's bags and send her to Kent.
国王的怒气一度...
The King's anger once...
再说一个字 我就揍你
Say one more word and I'll punch you.
国王已经说了必须当着整个议会的面 进行一场审问
The King has said there must be an inquiry, before the whole council.
如果安妮真的隐瞒了一桩秘密婚姻...
If Anne has concealed a secret marriage...
天啊 你闭嘴我真希望我能跟你离婚!
Jesus, I wish I could divorce you!
我真希望你有个婚前契约 但没这机会了
I wish you'd had a pre-contract. But no chance of that.
在这么下去 这里所有人全完了!
The fields were black with men running the other fucking way!
- 乔治!    - 我否认一切
- George!  - I deny everything.
- 很好    - 哈利 珀西 是说过爱我 我也认同了他的爱情
- Good.   - Harry Percy spoke of love, I'll allow that.
可我们之间根本就没有任何婚姻契约
But there was no contract.
也没有行房之事
And no consummation.
我妹妹是个名声不好的处女
My sister is a notorious virgin.
你跟国王说这事的时候 他态度如何
How was the King when you spoke to him?
如果不告诉克伦威尔大人事实真相  那叫他到这里来干什么
What is the use of calling in Master Cromwell and not telling him what has already occurred?
国王拂袖而去 留她独自站在那
The King walked out of the room and left her standing.
在我看来 这事有很多解决办法
It seems to me there are a number of approaches here.
噢 天哪!
Oh, Jesus Christ!
[我实在是不会翻了 有大神 请指点！]
By the thrice-beshitten shroud of Lazarus!
你还在慢慢选你的办法时 你的女儿
While you're selecting your approach, your daughter, sir,
在被人造谣中伤         - 哈利...   - 国王的思想已经被毒害
- is being slandered.  - Harry...  - The King's mind is poisoned,
而这个家族的财富 也会在你眼前灰飞烟灭!
and this family's fortune is unmaking before your fucking eyes!
能让我说句话么
Will you let me speak?
哈利 佩西曾被强制去忘记他的誓词
Harry Percy was persuaded once to forget his claim.
-如果他能再被强制一次...     - 的确如此 不过那时有红衣主教能压制他
- If he was fixed once...    - Yes. But the Cardinal fixed him then.
但很不幸 红衣主教现在死了
And unfortunately the Cardinal is dead.
安妮夫人
Lady Anne,
如果连教皇冕下都不能阻止您登上王后宝座
if the Pope cannot stop you becoming Queen -
当然 我也不认为他具备这样的能力
and I don't think he can -
那么 哈利 珀西就更没能力能阻拦您了
I don't see why Harry Percy should be allowed to stand in your way.
所以就直接把他赶回去呗
So shift him out of it.
做去吧
Do it.
真他妈想打爆他脑袋
Beat his fucking skull in.
上来玩玩啦
Why don't you come up?!
要找女人玩玩吗
Looking for a woman?
呵 我就猜到你会来了
Oh, God, yes, I thought you'd come.
嘿 出去
Hey  out.
你现在就是在浪费时间 安妮对我做过保证
Well, you're wasting your time. I was pledged to Anne.
我能陪她享受这闲暇时光
She allowed me such freedom with herself
做一个订婚的女人该做的事
as only a betrothed woman would allow.
那次红衣主教恐吓我 不许说任何事
The Cardinal bullied me out of saying anything last time,
现在我也不怕说出真相了
but I'm not afraid to speak the truth now.
阁下 你已经说了你该说的话了
My lord, you've said what you have to say.
现在 该轮到我说了
Now listen to me.
你是个一穷二白的人
You're a man whose money is almost spent.
我也对你了如指掌
I'm a man who knows how you've spent it.
你在全欧洲都已经是债台高筑了
You're a man who has borrowed all over Europe.
我也恰好知道你所有的欠债人姓甚名谁
I'm a man who knows your creditors.
只要我一句话 欠债条能瞬间把你淹没
One word from me, and all your debts will be called in.
他们能做什么呢 银行家可没有军队
What are they going to do? Bankers don't have armies.
分文没有的你 又拿什么保护自己
Neither will you, without any money.
阁下 国王赐予你伯爵爵位
My lord, you hold your earldom from the King.
是想让你为他守护北部边防 帮他抵御苏格兰的侵略
Your task is to secure the north, to defend us against Scotland.
如果你让他失望的话 国王毫无疑问 会收回你的封地和头衔
If you cannot ensure these things, the King will take your land
转而赏给那些
and your titles and give them
能力远在你之上的臣子
to someone who will do the job that you cannot do.
不 他不会的 他很尊重这些自古流传下来的家族头衔
No, he won't. He respects all ancient titles.
我该怎么向你解释呢
How can I explain this to you...?
这个世界已经不再是你所认为的那样了
The world is not run from where you think it is.
从边疆堡垒
From border fortresses.
甚至从白宫
Even from Whitehall.
从安特卫普 佛罗伦萨 里斯本
The world is run from Antwerp, from Florence, from Lisbon.
从那些商船们西行的扬帆之地开始 都变了
From wherever the merchant ships set sail off into the west.
不再是城堡的高墙，从数量有限的马匹开始
Not from castle walls, from counting houses.
从那些刮花本票的钢笔开始
From the pens that scrape out your promissory notes.
请相信我所说的
So believe me when I say
我会和我那些银行的朋友们一起 毁了你的人生
that my banker friends and I will rip your life apart.
然后 当你失去财产和头衔开始  是的  我都可以想象的出
And then, when you are without money and title, yes, I can picture you
你身处山洞 身着布衣的画面
living in a hovel, wearing homespun,
打回一只野兔 晚餐煮汤喝
bringing home a rabbit for the pot.
安妮 博林 你的合法妻子 为兔子剥皮 填料
Your lawful wife, Anne Boleyn, skinning and jointing that rabbit.
就是这样了 希望你幸福快乐
Yes, I wish you all happiness.
你从来都不会有所察觉
You were never pre-contracted.
只相信自己心里所想 可事实上 事与愿违
Any understanding you think you have, you didn't have it.
如果你认为 安妮夫人是真的爱你
And if you think Lady Anne loves you
你大错特错了
you couldn't be more mistaken.
我刚从她那儿过来
I've just come from her.
她很厌恶你
She hates you.
瞧不起你
She despises you.
恨不得你立马消失
She wants you gone.
所以 如果你再说一句和安妮夫人享受自由的话
So if you say one more word about Lady Anne's "freedom" with you,
你是在自掘坟墓
I will come and drag you out of whatever hole
而诺尔福克公爵也会把你的臭嘴撕裂
you are cowering in and the Duke of Norfolk will bite your bollocks off.
阁下 我这么解释 你应该明白了吧
I do hope that's clear, my lord?
来 你们随意偷看偷听吧
Yes, you can all peer in again.
他来了
There he is.
在他一连数月无政绩被免职之后 我和叔叔就来到这里工作
My uncle and I work for his removal for months without success
现在 他却辞职了
and now he resigns.
结算了工资
Over this bill.
他前途无量
His great protest.
英格兰对于他 只是一个小舞台
England is just a stage to him.
谁能会接替他的职位
Who should replace him?
想办法让国王任命 奥德利
Put it in the King's mind to appoint Audley.
他人不错 而且我想 他也很懂我的心思
He's a good man. And he understands me, I think.
根本没人了解
Do you think that someone does?
身为大主教的克兰麦
Cranmer as Archbishop,
身为大法官的奥德利
Audley as Lord Chancellor.
很快 哪里都有你的人了
Soon you'll have friends everywhere.
那你自己呢
And for yourself?
我想 也许是珠宝宫殿的看守员吧
I thought perhaps Keeper of the Jewel House?
办公室的锁链在哪 他应该是要交接的
Where's the chain of office? He's supposed to hand it over.
在那袋子里
In the bag.
所以就这样吗
So that's it?
莫尔就这样走了
More is out?
我们要下去么
Shall we go down?
你啊...
You...
你会承受不住的
you can't resist it.
- 你也一样          - 不会的
- No more can you.  - No.
你现在准备去干什么
What will you do now?
写书
Write.
祷告
Pray.
我的建议  少写 多祈祷
My recommendation - write only a little and pray a lot.
这算是威胁吗
Now, is that a threat?
也该轮到我了 是吧
My turn, don't you think?
我们要去加来
We're off to Calais.
法国国王已经同意 一道谏言教皇
The King of France had agreed to speak to the Pope
支持我的新婚姻
in favour of my new marriage.
我们要在加来见面 探讨谈判的内容
We'll meet there to discuss points of a treaty.
上次我们见面时
Last time we met,
沃尔西操办了所有事
Wolsey arranged everything.
这次我想你来安排
I thought perhaps you could help organise things this time?
靠着我 陛下
Lean on me, Your Majesty.
我们会带着大队人马到坎特伯雷
We'll take mass at Canterbury.
让人们朝见一下他们的国王
Let the people see their king.
你认识这个女人吗
Do you know this woman?
以前认识
I used to.
她让我想起了很久以前在安特卫普
She reminds me of someone I knew long ago.
认识的人
In Antwerp.
她叫什么名字
What was her name?
安赛姆
Anselma.
你知道什么是激情吗 克伦威尔
You've known passion, Cromwell.
和安妮...时 我会浑身颤抖
With Anne... I shake.
你明白我的意思？
Do you understand?
我颤抖了
I shake.
我也试过其他女人
I've tried other women,
想让她们激起我的强烈的欲望...
tried them just to try to take the edge off the lust...
但全都失败了
but I failed with all of them.
我做不到
Couldn't do it.
你不觉得这恰好是证明吗
Which is proof, don't you think?
证明我的追求是对的
Proof of the rightness of my pursuit.
我只追逐着一个女人
I hunt only one hind -
她引领我由幽径到达丛林深处...
and she takes me from the path and into the woods...
现在 回我们的冷被窝里去吧
Now, away to our cold beds.
还是只是我一个人的冷被窝
Or is that just mine?
你有的忙活了
There's work to do.
我有一项新职位给你
I have a new post for you.
我要你负责看管我的珍宝宫殿
I want you to be my Keeper of the Jewel House.
陛下
Your Majesty.
为什么不行 谁说我不可以？
Why not? Why shouldn't I?
谁说我不可以任用一个忠诚无二的铁匠的儿子
Who says I shouldn't employ the son of an honest blacksmith!
你的一切
Everything that you are,
你拥有的一切
everything that you have,
我都能赐予你
will come from me.
陛下！
Majesty!
这是那个圣女 让我见见她
This is the Holy Maid. Let me see her.
女士 你有什么想对我说的吗
Madam, you have something to say to me?
您应该烧死身边的那些异教分子
The heretics you have around you must be put into a great fire.
您如果不这么做 被烧死的会是您自己
If you don't do it, you'll burn yourself.
什么异教分子？ 我的人里面没有异端分子
What heretics? I keep no heretics about my person.
她就是 如果您和她结婚 您的王位在七个月之内将不保
Here's one. If you marry this one, you won't reign seven months.
你的谎话就不能编的像样点吗
Couldn't you at least round it up?
我见到了您的母亲 被幽冥鬼火包围着
I see your mother - surrounded by pale fires.
- 我母亲 在哪？         - 她疯了 应该把她鞭笞至死
- My mother? Where?     - She's mad. She should be whipped!
她可是圣女  她说的话只受上帝指引
She's a very holy person. Her speech is inspired by heaven.
你会遭雷劈的
Lightning will strike you!
在我踹死她前
Drag her back to the whorehouse
把她给我拖到妓院去！
before she feels my boot on her arse!
把她带走！带走！
Take her away! Take her away!
小姐？
Mistress?
我曾是已故的沃尔西主教的仆从
I was a servant of the late Cardinal Wolsey.
我知道你可以和死去的灵魂交流
I understand you can converse with the souls of the dead.
所以想知道您是否可以替我寻到他
Wondered if you would search for him for me.
您可以随便开价
I would be happy to make an offering.
那可是要给教堂一大笔捐赠的
It would have to be a generous donation.
没关系 我很富有
Well, I'm a wealthy man.
我得和博金神父商量一下
I'd have to talk to Father Bocking.
博金神父？
Father Bocking?
他是圣女的心灵导师
He is the lady's spiritual director.
噢
Ah.
下次再来找我问询吧
Come again and ask me.
嗯哼
Mm-hm.
跟我来
Come with me.
大人
My lord.
把你侄女带走吧
Fetch your niece away.
她已经外交够了
She has done enough diplomacy.
她在搞什么...
What the...
请原谅 陛下
By your leave, Highness.
夫人 我们去跳曲舞吧
My lady, we shall dance.
西摩大人 你的姐姐珍妮...
Master Seymour, your sister Jane...?
脾气很古怪对吧
Odd little creature, isn't she?
她多大了
How... old would she be?
不知道 二十岁左右？
I don't know. 20 or so?
她一直在狼厅周围四处走动
She keeps walking around Wolf Hall saying
还说这些都是托马斯 克伦威尔的爪牙
these are Thomas Cromwell's sleeves.
没人知道她在说什么
No-one knows what she's talking about.
你父亲难道没为她做媒么？
Has your father made her a match?
有一些议论...
There was some talk of...
你问这个干吗?
Why do you ask?
安妮想要一本圣经
Anne wants a Bible!
克伦威尔大人能背诵整个新约
Master Cromwell can recite the whole of the New Testament.
我觉得她是想用圣经起誓
I think she wants to swear on it.
噢 那我可能就不能去效劳了
Ah, then I probably won't do.
你怎么做到的?
How did you do that?
你
You.
我
Me.
她现在躺在他的臂弯里
She's in his arms.
全身赤裸 像刚出生婴儿一样
Naked as she was born.
她现在已经不能回头了
She can't change her mind now.
我以为他们刚刚是在吵架
I thought they were quarrelling.
的确是 他们喜欢争吵
They were. They like to quarrel.
那她要圣经做什么?
What did she want the Bible for?
让他在上帝的见证下起誓 他做了郑重承诺
To swear him. Before witnesses. He made her a binding promise.
他们在上帝的见证下结婚了
They are married in God's sight.
他也发誓说 一回到英格兰会再举行一次婚礼 为她戴上王后冠冕
And he swears he'll marry her again in England and crown her queen.
好吧 好吧 好吧
Well, well, well.
现在问题就是看他能不能把安妮吃掉了
So now it's just a question of whether he can do the deed.
看在上帝的份上 玛丽 别吓我
For God's sake, Mary, don't frighten me.
别担心 如果他胆怯了 安妮知道该怎么如愿
Don't worry. If he's shy, Anne will know how to help.
我已经教过她了
I've coached her.
是吗?
Have you?
那我们现在怎么办?
Now what about us?
为了让他们俩在一起 也算是经历了漫长的斗争
It's been a long struggle to bring them together.
我想我们已经得到消遣了
I think we've earned our recreation.
你不会还在怕我的叔叔 诺尔福克吧?
You're not still afraid of my Uncle Norfolk?
-我很害怕你的那个诺尔福克叔叔          - 但这不是原因 到底因为什么?
- I'm terrified of your Uncle Norfolk. - But it's not that. What is it?
另一个吗?
Another?
你差点杀了威廉 斯塔福德
You almost murdered William Stafford.
威廉 我还以为你不会来了
William, I thought you weren't coming.
看来你已经有备胎了啊
It seems you had a reserve ready, just in case.
你根本不懂一个女人的生活是怎样的！
You don't know what a woman's life is like!
你以为你已经跟一个男人有了些感情 但他却没出现
You think you've fixed something with a man, and he doesn't turn up!
祝你晚安
Give you good night.
不 别走
No, don't go.
我...呃...我该去祷告了
I, er... I think it's time I said my prayers.
你一直在信件往来切斯特
You've been writing letters up to Chester.
是关于陛下的事情 为什么这么问?
On his Majesty's business. Why?
我就说这一次 克伦威尔
I'll tell you this once, Cromwell.
别插手我的家事 不然我就要你好看
You keep out of my family's affairs or you'll have me to deal with.
而且你根本想象不到 你会变得有多糟糕
And you'll come off worse than you can possibly imagine.
你不该恐吓我的 阁下
You made a mistake threatening me, sir.
太初有道 道与神同在 道就是神
In the beginning was the Word and the Word was with God,
这道太初与神同在
and the Word was God.
万有是藉着他而成的
The same was in the beginning with God.
凡所成的
All things were made by it
没有一样不是藉着他而成的
and without it was made nothing that was made.
生命在他里面
In it was life
这生命就是人的光   [圣经 - 约翰福音]
and the life was the light of men.
我必须这样做 托马斯 我无法再背负着我所做之事活下去了
I had to, Thomas. I couldn't live with what I'd done.
那当你被宣判的时候呢...
When you're examined...
在最终宣判前 我会说出我该说的
I'll say what I will say before my last judge -
圣餐只不过是面包 我们没必要忏悔
that the Eucharist is only bread, we have no need of penance
炼狱也只是圣经中所创造的无稽之谈
and Purgatory is an invention ungrounded in scripture.
如果有人来 让你跟他们走 我希望你跟他们走
If some men come and tell you to go with them, I want you go with them.
那会是我派来的人
They'll be my men.
你觉得你能把我从伦敦塔里救出去吗?
You think you can get me out of the Tower?
汀代尔的圣经中说"有上帝在 万物皆存有可能"
Tyndale's Bible says "with God, nothing is impossible."
但那又有什么意义呢 托马斯
But what would be the point, Thomas?
我只需要走到保罗的十字架前
I'd only have to walk to Paul's cross
在伦敦人民面前说出我想说的话
and say before the Londoners what I've already said.
我不能不相信我的信仰
I cannot unbelieve what I believe.
所以 男性和女性之间确实有不相同 对吗
Therefore, is it not the same for the male sex and the female sex?
一方面 他们在一些
If on the one hand they appear different
技能或其他"职业"上 呈现出不同
with regard to some skill or other - employment?
职业
Occupation.
让我们单独聊聊 女儿
Leave us, daughter.
我可不想让你跟这个恶魔呆着
I won't have you in this devil's company.
我听说你不能出席加冕礼
I hear you can't come to the coronation
是因为你买不起一件新外套
because you can't afford a new coat.
伽迪纳会给你买件新外套的
Gardiner will buy you a new coat himself
- 如果你那天出现的话    - 他会吗?
- if you'll show your face on the day.  - Will he?
确实 能从他那儿拿走十磅都很不容易
Indeed. I'll relish taking the ten pounds from him.
那你要穿什么?
And what will you wear?
噢 他们正给我做新衣服呢 梅格
Oh, they're making me something, Meg.
我能不被嘲笑 就已经万幸了
If I avoid getting laughed at, it'll be enough.
我听说了圣女 那个姓巴顿的姑娘 来拜访过你
I heard the Holy Maid - the Barton girl - has been to visit you.
她的确来过 但是我们不会收留她的
She has. But we wouldn't receive her.
她还受艾可赛特夫人之邀 拜访过她家
She has also been to visit the Lady Exeter. At her invitation.
艾可赛特夫人 不过一介愚昧不堪且又野心勃勃的妇人
Lady Exeter is a foolish and ambitious woman.
巴顿告诉她 她有朝一日将会是英格兰的王后
Barton told her she'd be Queen of England.
仍执我见
I repeat my comment.
你也不相信她的眼力吗
You don't believe in her visions, then?
不相信 因为她是故意那么做的
I don't. She does it for attention.
我已经写信给她 建议她少伴在位高权重的人身边
I've written to her advising her to avoid the company
而是老实呆在家里祷告
of powerful men and women and to stay at home and pray.
我们所有人都该如此 以您为榜样
As should we all. Follow your example.
阿门 我猜您应该保留了一份副本吧
Amen. I suppose you've kept a copy?
梅格 去拿给他 否则他永远不会离开的
Get it, Meg. Otherwise he might never leave.
詹姆斯 班罕
James Bainham.
他将被施以火刑
He's to be burnt.
去求见亨利吧 他会像欢迎迷途浪子一样欢迎你归来
Ask to see Henry. He'll welcome you back like a lost child.
我不是让你支持詹姆斯的观点
I'm not asking you to agree with James.
如果他的信仰有误 你可以劝他回去 回罗马去
If his doctrine is false, you can talk him back, back to Rome.
你能言善辩
You're an eloquent man.
是我们这个时代最卓越的辩论家
You're the great persuader of our age.
但如果他驾鹤西征 你永远不会知道
But if he dies, you'll never know, will you?
你是否能够救赎他的灵魂 对吧
Whether you could have saved his soul.
你不能进去 她尚未更衣
You can't come in. She's in a state of undress.
让他进来吧
Let him in.
国王陛下说您此时美过往昔
The King says you've never looked more beautiful.
他让我转达一个吻 我说他还是应该亲自送达为好
And he sends a kiss, which I told him he should deliver himself.
你穿的这是什么？
What are you wearing?
我说过不要穿黑色的
I said no black.
这是深红色
It's scarlet.
是深的发黑的红
It's a very black scarlet.
佛朗西斯 布莱恩说我看起来就像一块会行走的淤青肿块
Francis Bryan says I look like a walking bruise.
你听到他们为我欢呼了么
Did you hear them cheer for me?
所有的言论都在说人们爱戴凯瑟琳
All this talk of people loving Katherine.
我认为他们不过是怜悯她而已
I think they just pity her.
噢不 他们爱戴她
Oh, no, they love her
因为她是两位受膏的君主之女［在国王登基仪式或授予神职仪式上涂膏油于人使其神圣化 ］
because she is the daughter of two anointed sovereigns.
他们永远不会像爱戴凯瑟琳一样爱戴您的 至多...
They'll never love you like that Madam, any more than...
就像爱戴这个克伦威尔一样而已
Cromwell here.
您最好也能接受这点 我认为...
You may as well make your mind to it. I think...
够了 珍妮
That's enough, Jane.
他们说巴顿小女孩已经预言了
They say the Barton girl has prophesied
那个所谓的玛丽公主以后会成为女王
that so-called Princess Mary will be queen.
凯瑟琳正与艾可赛特以及波尔密谋
Katherine is plotting with Exeter and Pole -
她们都曾是金雀花王朝的人
all the old Plantagenets.
- 您不要徒增烦恼  - 我不是自寻烦恼
- Don't distress yourself. - I'm not distressed.
这些人巴不得我死
These people want me dead.
但一旦我儿子出生 他们就都无能为力了
But when my son is born, they'll all be powerless.
克伦威尔大人
Master Cromwell?
我想要感谢您
I wanted to thank you.
收到了您的礼物
From your present.
托马斯 克伦威尔的袖子
Thomas Cromwell's sleeves.
狼厅的事情如何了
How do things stand at Wolf Hall?
爱德华愤怒至极 我母亲也咬牙切齿暗自生气
Edward is angry, my mother is grinding her teeth.
我想要离开
I would like to leave.
好吧 如果我是你父亲...
Well, if I were your father...
如果我建议的话 建议你留下
If I were to advise you, it would be to stay
效忠你们的新王后
in the service of your new queen.
谦逊恭顺总是适宜的 而且她总是确保我们如此
Well, it's good to be humble. And she makes sure we are.
我相信她会变温和的 如今她内心已经有了渴望
I think she'll soften, now she has her heart's desire.
我谦逊恭顺时就是这样的
This is my humble face.
可以么
Will it serve?
我觉得它让你到哪 都如鱼得水的
I think it would take you anywhere.
它是今天送来的
It came for you today.
国王赏赐您的礼物
A present from the King.
王后准备开始闭居
The Queen is setting off to begin her confinement.
我们只是想确认一下
We just wanted to check.
我们应该说"宣布一位王子的诞生"
Are we saying "announcing the birth of a prince"
还是只是说一个"孩子"的诞生
or just the birth of a "child?"
- 我们所有人的命运都系在这夫人身上了
- All of our fortunes depend on this lady now
看她能否诞下继承人了
and whether she can provide an heir,
我们都知道一个尚在腹中的孩子 和一个已经安然躺在婴儿床里的孩子
and we all know it's a long road between a child in the womb
不可同日而语
and one safely in the crib.
你看起来很高兴
You look happy.
你高兴么
Are you happy?
开心
Yes.
因为这孩子
Because of this.
过去我总是想要很多
I was always desired.
但是现在我很知足 你知道么?
But now I'm valued, you see?
而这孩子就是不同之处
And that's different.
彼以国士待我，我以国士待之，用过免费优质字幕服务，
而又有能力的人，有义务将这个免费服务做下去若有心加入我们 联系：dajiazimuzu@163.com